{"question": "\u201cMay the Fourth be with you\u201d is the official tagline of the galaxy-wide holiday celebrated the first week of May in honor of what sci-fi franchise?", "answer": " Star Wars"}
{"question": "What 2018 Star Wars film focuses on the early adventures of Chewbacca and the character who was portrayed by Harrison Ford in \"A New Hope,\" \"The Empire Strikes Back,\" and \"Return of the Jedi?\"", "answer": " Solo"}
{"question": "\"Rogue One\" was a 2016 standalone feature film starring Felicity Jones within the universe (er, galaxy) of what film franchise?", "answer": " Star Wars"}
{"question": "What Admiral in the rebellion, a member of the Mon Calamari race, famously exclaimed \u201cIt\u2019s a trap!\u201d during the climactic space battle at the end of \u201cReturn Of The Jedi?\u201d", "answer": " Admiral Ackbar"}
{"question": "Sure to mess up Star Wars Day, 63.4% of Texas tornadoes between 1951 and 2016 struck during what month of the year?", "answer": " May"}
{"question": "The Empire Strikes Back hit theaters during Memorial Day Weekend in 1980. That same week, an iconic horror film opened but had a relatively weak opening box office because it was counter-programmed against the Star Wars installment. What was this Jack Nicholson-starring horror film?", "answer": " The Shining"}
{"question": "What bipeds, native to the forest moon of Endor, play a major role in the destruction of the second death star in Return of the Jedi?", "answer": " Ewoks"}
{"question": "With ten appearances, Anthony Daniels holds the record for actor who has appeared in the most \"Star Wars\" films, playing what shiny, alphanumerically named character?", "answer": " C3PO"}
{"question": "Gina Carano plays what rebel turned mercenary who often helps the titular bounty hunter on Disney+\u2019s \u201cThe Mandalorian?\u201d Her last name is the same as a different sci-fi franchise created by Frank Herbert.", "answer": " Cara Dune"}
{"question": "Star Wars fan Mike J. Nichols released a fan edit of \"Episode I \u2013 The Phantom Menace\" entitled \"The Phantom Edit\" in which, along with other smaller changes, he almost entirely removed which controversial character voiced by Ahmed Best?", "answer": " Jar Jar Binks"}
{"question": "Alden Ehrenreich played what occasionally smug but generally well-intentioned Star Wars character in a 2018 spin-off prequel movie? He is known for wearing a vest and for being called scruffy looking.", "answer": " Han Solo"}
{"question": "What agile and murderous Sith Lord with a double lightsaber, trained by Darth Sidious, has been portrayed by Ray Park in \u201cStar Wars Episode I: The Phantom Menace\u201d and \u201cSolo: A Star Wars Story?\u201d", "answer": " Darth Maul"}
{"question": "James Earl Jones said he only made $7,000 for his role as which character in \u201cStar Wars: A New Hope?\u201d", "answer": " Darth Vader"}
{"question": "George Lucas is on record saying that its shape was inspired by a hamburger, how is the light freighter YT-1300 492727ZED better known?", "answer": " The Millennium Falcon"}
{"question": "In the 2018 film \u201cSolo: A Star Wars Story,\u201d Lando Calrissian was portrayed by which actor who\u2019s better known in the music business as Childish Gambino?", "answer": " Donald Glover"}
{"question": "What Star Wars character, the grandson of Shmi Lars, worked on a family moisture farm on Tatooine, although perhaps he was meant for something greater?", "answer": " Luke Skywalker"}
{"question": "Although during the majority of the films he is not called \u201cChancellor Palpatine,\u201d what science fiction series sees Ian McDiarmid fairly elected as the head of the Galactic Senate in Episode 1?", "answer": " Star Wars"}
{"question": "In May 2022, Star Wars fans were saddened by the passing of Colin Cantwell, whose most famous designs included those for what gigantic weapon destroyed at the end of \"A New Hope?\"", "answer": " Death Star"}
{"question": "What starfighter used by the Rebel Alliance in the Star Wars films has four laser cannons and two proton torpedo launchers? It gets its name because the way it extends has a distinct shape that resembles a letter.", "answer": " X-Wing Starfighter"}
{"question": "As shown in detail in \u201cSolo: A Star Wars Story\u201d, Han Solo made a legendary accomplishment when he raced across what dangerous space \u201cRun\u201d in a record 12 parsecs?", "answer": " Kessel Run"}
{"question": "What member of the Jedi council, armed with a grim attitude and an amethyst-colored lightsaber, was played by Samuel L. Jackson in the Star Wars prequels?", "answer": " Mace Windu"}
{"question": "Daisy Ridley made her first appearance as Rey in which 3-word Star Wars film?", "answer": " The Force Awakens"}
{"question": "Troy Kotsur, who won Best Supporting Actor for \u201cCoda\u201d at the 2022 Academy Awards, played a member of what \u201cT\u201d desert alien race on \u201cThe Mandalorian?\u201d They are typically depicted as desert raiders, prone to bouts of anger.", "answer": " Tusken"}
{"question": "Of the two live-action \"stand alone\" movies (i.e., not part of one of the trilogies) which takes place first chronologically? It was the second of the live-action stand alone movies in term of theatrical release, however. (There was also an animated film.)", "answer": " Solo: A Star Wars Story"}
{"question": "In May 2018, a Star Wars spinoff film was released that followed the journeys of Han Solo. What is the name of Solo's bipedal, hirsute sidekick from the planet of Kashyyyk?", "answer": " Chewbacca"}
{"question": "In \u201cStar Wars Episode II: Attack Of The Clones\u201d, Anakin Skywalker tells Padme Amidala that he doesn\u2019t like what 4-letter yellow biproduct of rock erosion, claiming \u201cit\u2019s course and rough and irritating, and it gets everywhere?\u201d", "answer": " Sand"}
{"question": "Who was the first character to speak in the first Star Wars movie? This anxiety-ridden sidekick stands five feet and eight inches tall.", "answer": " C3PO"}
{"question": "Darth Vader is famously misquoted with \"Luke, I am your father.\" Darth Vader does not say \"Luke\" in that pivotal moment. What word did he say instead?", "answer": " No"}
{"question": "What 2021 Disney+ series allows seven Japanese animation studios to bring their unique perspectives to the Star Wars universe, through short films? It is a plural word for seeing something concrete through a dream or trance.", "answer": " Star Wars: Visions"}
{"question": "More commonly heard in relation to bald heads, what rhyming pair of words does Finn call Captain Phasma after she calls him a \"bug in the system\" in Episode VIII - The Last Jedi?", "answer": " Chrome Dome"}
{"question": "Sir Alec Guinness was nominated for Best Supporting Actor at the 50th Academy Awards for portraying what Jedi Knight in the first Star Wars film?", "answer": " Obi-Wan Kenobi"}
{"question": "What large, hairy mammals with spiral horns inhabit the planet Tatooine and are used by other species for products such as meat and butter? They first appear in the first film of the \u201cStar Wars\u201d film series.", "answer": " Bantha"}
{"question": "\"Star Wars: Galaxy's Edge,\" in which visitors can \"fly\" the Millennium Falcon, is an area of what Anaheim, California theme park that first opened in 1955?", "answer": " Disneyland"}
{"question": "Which kind of crystal powers a lightsaber, as well as the superlaser of the Death Star?", "answer": " Kyber"}
{"question": "Spoken by Princess Leia after Han Solo says he won't get in the way of her relationship with Luke, what two words complete the final line of Return of the Jedi: It's not like that at all. He's ...?", "answer": " ...my brother"}
{"question": "What character from the Star Wars prequels was Queen and later Senator of Naboo, although a tragic marriage to a talented Jedi master would cause her problems? She was played by Natalie Portman in the films.", "answer": " Padme Amidala"}
{"question": "What number was the Order created by the Galactic Republic, which secretly branded all Jedi as enemies of the Republic and subject to direct execution? It is the same number as the Will Rogers Highway, a famous Route spanning from Chicago to Los Angeles.", "answer": " Order 66"}
{"question": "What is the name of the Moff played by Giancarlo Esposito in the Disney+ series \u201cThe Mandalorian\u201d, who seeks to rebuild the Galactic Empire by capturing the Baby Yoda known as Grogu? He shares a name with a biblical prophet known for his calling and later victory over the Midianites.", "answer": " Moff Gideon"}
{"question": "In \"The Phantom Menace,\" Padm\u00e9 Amidala, portrayed by Natalie Portman, becomes the 14-year-old queen of which bountiful green planet in the Star Wars universe?", "answer": " Naboo"}
{"question": "Although he had a much more famous actor providing his voice, David Prowse was inside the suit of what major villain of the original Star Wars trilogy?", "answer": " Darth Vader"}
{"question": "What kind of tree primarily made up the California forest land used for the Endor scenes in \"Return of the Jedi?\"", "answer": " Redwood"}
{"question": "Featuring in Episode VI: Return of the Jedi, the scenes of the forest moon of Endor were shot in and around a national park in which U.S. state?", "answer": " California"}
{"question": "In order to agree to a role in the Star Wars prequel films, actor Samuel L. Jackson requested that his character's lightsaber would be what color? The request was eventually accepted.", "answer": " Purple"}
{"question": "In \u201cThe Mandalorian,\u201d the character is known as Baby Yoda, or even just \u201cThe Child,\u201d but it turns out he actually goes by what \u201cG\u201d name?", "answer": " Grogu"}
{"question": "Played by Christopher Lee in \"Attack of the Clones\" and \"Revenge of the Sith\", what is the Sith name of former Jedi Master Count Dooku?", "answer": " Darth Tyranus"}
{"question": "A major plot hole in the \"Star Wars\" franchise is Leia claiming to remember her mother in \"Return of the Jedi,\" despite Padme Amidala dying in childbirth in which prequel movie?", "answer": " Episode III: Revenge of the Sith"}
{"question": "What Canadian actor, who played the young Anakin Skywalker in Star Wars Episodes II and III, came back to play Darth Vader in the 2022 Disney+ miniseries \"Obi-Wan Kenobi?\"", "answer": " Hayden Christensen"}
{"question": "Clocking in at 2 hours and 32 minutes (according to its IMDB.com runtime), which of the 9 movies in the Skywalker Saga is the longest?", "answer": " The Last Jedi"}
{"question": "What five-letter name is shared by a realm in Robert Jordan's \"The Wheel of Time\" series and an upcoming Disney+ show starring Diego Luna as a thief turned rebel?", "answer": " Andor"}
{"question": "Used as an alias of another major character in the original trilogy, what first name did Han Solo and Leia Organa give their son before he changed his name to Kylo Ren?", "answer": " Ben"}
{"question": "In \u201cStar Wars: Episode II \u2013 Attack of the Clones,\u201d on which planet does Obi-Wan uncover the clone army?", "answer": " Kamino"}
{"question": "In \u201cStar Wars: The Clone Wars,\u201d voice actor Kevin Michael Richardson portrayed what massive, slimy villain who first appeared in \u201cStar Wars: Episode VI \u2013 Return of the Jedi?\u201d", "answer": " Jabba The Hut"}
{"question": "A military program announced by President Reagan in March 1983 promoted funding for lasers and particle beam weapons and was formally known as the Strategic Defense Initiative. However, what two-word name was the program (somewhat mockingly) nicknamed by the public?", "answer": " Star Wars"}
{"question": "What ice planet is the area where the first big battle of \"The Empire Strikes Back\" takes place?", "answer": " Hoth"}
{"question": "\"Exsqueeze me\", \"I spake\", and \"Oh, Gooberfish!\" are lines spoken by which divisive character in \"Star Wars: Episode 1- The Phantom Menace?\"", "answer": " Jar Jar Binks"}
{"question": "Although viewers learn eventually that she is a Skywalker by birth, what is the surname of Princess Leia that is taken from her adoptive parents?", "answer": " Organa"}
{"question": "On which planet in the Outer Rim Territories do we see Ponda Baba (aka \"Walrus Man\") lose an arm while the song \"Mad About Me\" plays in the background?", "answer": " Tatooine (in the Mos Eisley Cantina)"}
{"question": "What first name did Obi-Wan use while exiled on Tatooine? (Hint: It\u2019s also how he\u2019s introduced in the first film)", "answer": " Ben"}
{"question": "Attacked Luke in the Jundland Waste. Blasted potshots at pod racers in \"Phantom Menace.\" Helped The Mandalorian beat a krayt dragon. What outdoorsy people am I talking about?", "answer": " Tusken Raiders"}
{"question": "What Star Wars console video game released at the end of 2020 focuses on space combat inspired by the movie franchise? The title comes from the operational air force units comprised of two or more aircraft and their personnel.", "answer": " Star Wars: Squadrons"}
{"question": "A world record holder for faking out stormtroopers about droid identities, the O.G. Obi-Wan Kenobi in 1977's \"Star Wars\" was played by Sir Alec WHO?", "answer": " Guinness"}
{"question": "At the start of the original trilogy (now the 4th movie), the viewer learns that Yoda has been living in exile on what swampy planet?", "answer": " Dagobah"}
{"question": "Blink-182 sings, \"And of course I'd do anything for her, I'd search the moons of Endor\" in what 1997 song that's named after a Star Wars episode?", "answer": " A New Hope"}
{"question": "What \u201cG\u201d Rodian bounty with green skin famously cornered Han Solo in the Mos Eisley Cantina in \u201cStar Wars Episode IV: A New Hope,\u201d only to get shot for his efforts? His name kind of sounds like another word for avarice.", "answer": " Greedo"}
{"question": "In the infamous Star Wars Holiday Special, which character is revealed to have a son named Lumpawaroo (a.k.a. Lumpy)?", "answer": " Chewbacca"}
{"question": "The United States' proposed Strategic Defense Initiative was often best known by what pop-culture nickname, which it received in a 1983 article in the Washington Post?", "answer": " Star Wars"}
{"question": "At the start of \u201cStar Wars: Episode III \u2013 Revenge of the Sith,\u201d Obi-Wan is on the hunt for which villain he must defeat in order to end the war? (Hint: The alliteratively named character was CGI-animated and voiced by Matthew Wood)", "answer": " General Grievous"}
{"question": "Which 2005 \u201cStar Wars\u201d film marked the first appearance of Order 66?", "answer": " Revenge of the Sith"}
{"question": "What legendary effects company was founded by George Lucas in 1975 to provide effects for the Star Wars franchise?", "answer": " Industrial Light & Magic"}
{"question": "Danoga is the dangerous creature that lives inside what appliance/room/large machinery on the original Death Star?", "answer": " Garbage Compactor"}
{"question": "Born John Adedayo Bamidele Adegboyega but known by the shorter John Boyega professionally, what character was played by this British-Nigerian actor in the Star Wars franchise?", "answer": " Finn"}
{"question": "2021 saw the release of what animated TV show, a continuation of the Clone Wars saga created by Dave Filoni and starring Ming-Na Wen and Freddie Prinze, Jr.? The two-word alliterative title implies these post-Clone War Clones are not the greatest.", "answer": " Bad Batch"}
{"question": "The Trans-Alaska Pipeline System started operating at the height of the oil crisis and the height of \"Star Wars\" mania in what year of the 1970s?", "answer": " 1977"}
{"question": "In most television, novel, and comic book appearances of the Empire's Grand Admiral Thrawn, what color is the character's skin?", "answer": " Blue"}
{"question": "It's a bit unsurprising that Temuera played Boba Fett in the second season of The Mandalorian given that the New Zealander played what previous Star Wars character in the film's prequel trilogy?", "answer": " Jango Fett"}
{"question": "\"Star Wars: Tales from the Galaxy's Edge\" is a virtual reality adventure game released in November 2020 for what VR headset system?", "answer": " Oculus"}
{"question": "In 2021, Bandai issued an R2-D2 edition of what handheld toy, whose name is a blend of the Japanese words for \"egg\" and \"watch\"?", "answer": " Tamagotchi"}
{"question": "In a 2021 poll by Slashfilm.com, what evil emperor also known as Darth Sidious was voted the worst \"Star Wars\" character of all time?", "answer": " Palpatine"}
{"question": "The first Star Wars video game, made for the Atari 2600, was based on which film in the original trilogy?", "answer": " The Empire Strikes Back"}
{"question": "What actor, who originated one of the most famous roles in the \"Star Wars\" franchise, later told The Guardian, \"Apart from the money, I regret having embarked on the film?\"", "answer": " Alec Guinness"}
{"question": "The original \u201cStar Wars Holiday Special\u201d aired on CBS in 1978 and marked the first appearance of which character? (Hint: The bounty hunter was voiced by Don Francks in the special and was later played by Jeremy Bulloch with voice acting by Jason Wingreen).", "answer": " Boba Fett"}
{"question": "What iconic two-word response did Harrison Ford ad-lib in The Empire Strikes Back?", "answer": " I know"}
{"question": "What \u201cR\u201d name applies to a giant creature from Dathomir, that Jabba The Hut keeps in a cave to eat people he doesn\u2019t like in \u201cReturn Of The Jedi?\u201d Eating Luke Skywalker doesn\u2019t go that well.", "answer": " Rancor"}
{"question": "First revealed in \"Attack of the Clones,'\" what villainous character was in fact the Jedi Master that took Qui-Gon Jinn as his apprentice?", "answer": " Count Dooku"}
{"question": "In 1985, what was the name of the \u201cStar Wars\u201d animated series that revolved around C-3PO and R2D2, not old Motorola phones? (Hint: It\u2019s often paired with \u201cEwoks,\u201d another animated series that aired at the same time)", "answer": " Droids"}
{"question": "What hyperspace route passing by the Maw nebula did Han Solo traverse in the Millenium Falcon using a route that was roughly 40% shorter than was previously thought possible?", "answer": " The Kessel Run"}
{"question": "What is the four-letter name for the species of traders that capture R2-D2 and C-3PO before selling them to moisture farmer Luke Skywalker?", "answer": " Jawa"}
{"question": "Y-wing fighters are equipped with what kind of cannons that sound pretty positively charged?", "answer": " Ion cannons"}
{"question": "After denying the initial reports, what man admitted in January 2013 that he was leaving the Star Trek franchise to direct the return of the Star Wars series return with Episode VII?", "answer": " JJ Abrams"}
{"question": "What Star Wars character was introduced as the Padawan apprentice of Anakin Skywalker in the animated film \"The Clone Wars\" and also starred in the TV series of the same name?", "answer": " Ahsoka Tano"}
{"question": "The only non-Jedi to wield a lightsaber in the original \"Star Wars\" trilogy was Han Solo, when he cut open what thing?", "answer": " TaunTaun"}
{"question": "In the affectionate Star Wars parody, \u201cSpace Balls,\u201d the film renames the slimy crime lord \u201cJabba\u201d to something far less sinister and perhaps a bit more delicious. What is this character\u2019s new name?", "answer": " Pizza the Hut"}
{"question": "The Jawa Ion Blaster, Imperial Sandtroopers's Big Gun, and Boba Fett's Blaster are all guns found in what famous fictional franchise?", "answer": " Star Wars"}
{"question": "What small Brooklyn-based ice cream brand scored a huge \"Star Wars\" movie tie-in when it made \"Dark Side\" and \"Light Side\" flavors inspired by \"The Last Jedi?\"", "answer": " Ample Hills"}
{"question": "During the \u201890s, Lockheed Martin developed the graphics system for what video game company\u2019s Model 3 system for arcade games including \u201cVirtua Fighter 3\u201d, \u201cSpikeOut\u201d, and \u201cStar Wars Trilogy Arcade\u201d?", "answer": " Sega"}
{"question": "Cassian Andor, a Rebel intelligence officer and captain of the titular \u201cRogue One\u201d in the 2016 film, as well as the star of the 2022 Disney+ show \u201cAndor\u201d, is played by what Mexican actor? He has also starred in such films as \u201cY tu mama tambien\u201d and \u201cMilk.\u201d", "answer": " Diego Luna"}
{"question": "What \u201cM\u201d Welsh director was at the helm of 1983\u2019s \u201cReturn Of The Jedi?\u201d His other movies include \u201cEye Of The Needle\u201d and \u201cJagged Edge.\u201d", "answer": " Richard Marquand"}
{"question": "What streetwear brand, whose name is a word meaning \"friends and relatives,\" debuted a 54-piece Star Wars-themed collection in December 2021 featuring Stormtrooper sweaters, a C-3PO waffle-knit tee, and other items?", "answer": " Kith"}
{"question": "What actress, star of \u201cLeon: The Professional\u201d and the Star Wars franchise, graduated from Harvard University with a BA in psychology in 2003?", "answer": " Natalie Portman"}
{"question": "For two seasons in the 1980s, what animated \"Star Wars\" series followed the adventures of Wicket W. Warwick and his friends on the forest moon of Endor?", "answer": " Ewoks"}
{"question": "What comic book company published the original \"Star Wars\" comic book series that ran from 1977 to 1987, and included 107 issues and three annuals?", "answer": " Marvel"}
{"question": "What toy manufacturer produced the first Star Wars action figures?", "answer": " Kenner"}
{"question": "What \u201cH\u201d Star Wars character is an alien in the Mos Eisley Cantina in \u201cStar Wars: Episode IV\u201d, with a large brown head that resembles a banging hardware tool? His compound word name is the same as a shark with a similarly large head.", "answer": " Hammerhead"}
{"question": "What Northern Irish actor, known for \u201cSchindler\u2019s List\u201d and the \u201cTaken\u201d franchise, played Qui-Gon Jinn in \u201cStar Wars Episode I: The Phantom Menace?\u201d", "answer": " Liam Neeson"}
{"question": "What \u201cG\u201d Star Wars robot and General was known as a feared Jedi hunter with multiple robotic limbs in \u201cStar Wars: Episode III\u201d and the \u201cClone Wars\u201d franchise? His name is also an adjective for a severe or serious blow.", "answer": " General Grievous"}
{"question": "In \u201cReturn Of The Jedi,\u201d Oola is the dancer sent off to be killed by the rancor owned by what fat, slimy, \u201cJ\u201d Hutt?", "answer": " Jabba The Hut"}
{"question": "In \u201cFortnite,\u201d video game combatants can use what \u201cL\u201d Star Wars weapon? The chosen weapon of the Jedi, it is in essence a laser blade, created by careful manipulation of rare crystals.", "answer": " Lightsaber"}
{"question": "The impossibility of removing large flocks of puffins from Skellig Michael, the real-life location that represents Ahch-To in \"The Last Jedi,\" led to the design of what cute and cuddly creatures?", "answer": " Porgs"}
{"question": "Retail employees Randal and Dante earnestly discuss the killing of innocent civilians on the Second Death Star in \"Return of the Jedi,\" in what 1994 black-and-white Kevin Smith film?", "answer": " Clerks"}
{"question": "George Lucas originally dreamed that one of the most famous actor/directors of the era would voice Darth Vader. In the end, Lucas decided that the voice of which famous man\u2014known for \u201cCitizen Kane\u201d and \u201cThe War of the Worlds\u201d\u2014was just too iconic and therefore too easy for audiences to recognize?", "answer": " Orson Welles"}
{"question": "The planet of Tatooine is part of a binary star system. Its two suns share what name, being distinguished only by Roman numerals following this name?", "answer": " Tatoo (Tatoo I and Tatoo II)"}
{"question": "The first film in the Skywalker Saga, which Star Wars movie (Episode I) was released in 1999 and starred Liam Neeson, Ewan McGregor, and Natalie Portman?", "answer": " The Phantom Menace"}
{"question": "What is the name of the carnivorous creature from Tatooine that C-3PO is talking about when he says, \"In its belly, you will find a new definition of pain and suffering, as you are slowly digested over a thousand years\"\u2014?", "answer": " Sarlacc"}
{"question": "In Star Wars: The Phantom Menace, what is the name of the Xexto podracer pilot who finishes second to Anakin Skywalker in the Boonta Eve Classic Podrace?", "answer": " Gasgano"}
{"question": "The newest area at Disney Theme Parks is a Star Wars-themed experience that opened in 2019 at both Disneyland and Disney World's Hollywood Studios. What two-word name, referring to the remote frontier planet Batuu, do these themed areas share?", "answer": " Galaxy's Edge"}
{"question": "What\u2019s the A-name of the species that could pass for humans as long as their tentacle-like projections were hidden in their cheeks, and they weren\u2019t drinking Force soup?", "answer": " Anzati"}
{"question": "Also the number of years separating the births of Harrison Ford and Carrie Fisher, how many years old is Padme when she is elected Queen of Naboo in The Phantom Menace?", "answer": " 14"}
{"question": "The screenplay for \u201cStar Wars Episode II \u2013 Attack of the Clones\u201d (2002) was co-written by George Lucas and which British screenwriter who had written for the British TV war drama \u201cManhunt\u201d in the \u201870s?", "answer": " Jonathan Hales"}
{"question": "In the early \u201890s, which series of young adult sci-fi novels written by Paul and Hollace Davids told of the adventures of Luke, Leia, and Han? (Hint: The books were set about a year after the events of \u201cReturn of the Jedi\u201d)", "answer": " Jedi Prince"}
{"question": "\u201cStar Wars: The Clone Wars\u201d was the first film in the franchise to be distributed by Warner Bros. Pictures instead of which studio?", "answer": " 20th Century Fox"}
{"question": "As one of the most versatile voice actors in the \u201cStar Wars\u201d franchise, who gave Frank Oz a break and voiced Yoda in the \u201cClone Wars\u201d films and various TV shows and video games in the 2000s?", "answer": " Tom Kane"}
{"question": "Five men with the same four-letter first name won Oscars for the first Star Wars film - Mr. Barry won for Art Direction, Mr. Mollo for Costume Design, Mr. Williams for Original Score, and Mr. Stears and Mr. Dykstra for Visual Effects. What name did they share?", "answer": " John"}
{"question": "In the whole nine movies of the Skywalker Saga, which character has the most combined screen time?", "answer": " Anakin Skywalker/Darth Vader"}
{"question": "In Episode IV, Han Solo famously misuses what unit of distance, which is equal to 3.26 light-years, as a unit of time, when he says that the Millennium Falcon made the Kessel run in 12 of them?", "answer": " Parsecs"}
{"question": "President Ronald Reagan borrowed what alliterative phrase from Star Wars in a 1983 speech about the Soviet Union?", "answer": " Evil Empire"}
{"question": "Which actor, who passed away in 1994 was digitally brought back to life in the 2016 Star Wars canon movie \u2018Rogue One\u2019?", "answer": " Peter Cushing"}
{"question": "A member of Michigan's Class of 1955, what bass-voiced actor is known for, among other roles, providing the voice of Darth Vader in \"Star Wars\" and of Mufasa in \"The Lion King?\"", "answer": " James Earl Jones"}
{"question": "Also known as \u201cDarth Vader\u2019s theme\u201d and written by John Williams, what is the only movie in the nine-part Skywalker saga where the piece of music called \u201cThe Imperial March\u201d is not featured at all?", "answer": " Episode IV A New Hope"}
{"question": "It begins with \"A\", and ends in \"O\", but contains no other vowels. On what planet (said to be the \"most unfindable place in the galaxy\" does Rey find Luke Skywalker at the end of The Force Awakens?", "answer": " Ahch-To"}
{"question": "George Lucas has the most screenwriting credits in Episodes I through IX of Star Wars. Who has the second most screenwriting credits?", "answer": " Lawrence Kasdan"}
{"question": "Seen in Return of the Jedi, Chief Chirpa is the leader of a tribe of what species of creature?", "answer": " Ewoks"}
{"question": "A 1984 Star Wars spinoff film follows what fluffy puppet creatures who live on the Moon of Endor, and who were first introduced in Return of the Jedi?", "answer": " Ewoks"}
{"question": "Which actor, who is known for his lead role in Quentin Tarantino\u2019s \u2018Hateful Eight\u2019, unsuccessfully auditioned for the role of Luke Skywalker?", "answer": " Kurt Russell"}
{"question": "Star Wars movies are often interesting for their cameos. Of the final trilogy (not counting \"Rogue One\" or \"Solo\"), which movie includes cameos by, among others, Ed Sheeran (as a stormtrooper), Lin Manuel Miranda (as a soldier), Kevin Smith (as an inhabitant of Kijimi), and composer John Williams (as a character named Oma Tres)?", "answer": " The Rise of Skywalker"}
{"question": "Passing away in 2013 at the age of 98, Stuart Freeborn was the supervisor of which department in the production of Episode IV in 1977?", "answer": " Makeup"}
{"question": "Which actor played Unkar Plutt, a member of the Crolute species residing on Jakku in Episode VII: The Force Awakens?", "answer": " Simon Pegg"}
{"question": "As seen in Episodes I-III, how many spires does the Jedi Temple on Coruscant have?", "answer": " Five"}
{"question": "Which Star Wars character's final line before dying is \"Tell your sister... you were right\"?", "answer": " Anakin Skywalker / Darth Vader"}
{"question": "Which 1998 Brad Pitt Movie is infamous as a lot of people paid to see the movie and left early because they only wanted to see the Episode trailer before it?", "answer": " Meet Joe Black"}
{"question": "By blending the sounds of a bear, a lion, a badger, and a walrus, sound designer Ben Burtt created the iconic voice of which Star Wars character?", "answer": " Chewbacca"}
{"question": "Of the three original Star Wars movies, which had the longest time elapse between the film's release and its induction into the Library of Congress's National Film Registry?", "answer": " Return of the Jedi"}
{"question": "What many people consider the best movie in the series, \"The Empire Strikes Back,\" was co-written by Leigh Brackett and what screenwriter/director of \"The Big Chill\"?", "answer": " Lawrence Kasdan"}
{"question": "Legend has it that George Lucas was inspired to come up with which Star Wars character after his dog, an Alaskan Malamute, who could easily be mistaken for a person when he\u2019d ride shot gun in the car?", "answer": " Chewbacca"}
{"question": "According to a quote by Padme Amidala in 'Star Wars Episode III', what dies with thunderous applause?", "answer": " Liberty"}
{"question": "After escaping Jabba the Hut\u2019s palace in \"Star Wars: Episode VI \u2013 Return of the Jedi,\" Luke Skywalker returns to what murky \u201cD\u201d planet to finish training as a Jedi with Yoda?", "answer": " Dagobah"}
{"question": "How old was young Anakin Skywalker in Star Wars: Episode I \u2013 The Phantom Menace? (Hint: It\u2019s the same as the episode number of \u201cStar Wars: The Rise of Skywalker.\u201d)", "answer": " 9"}
{"question": "What color is Bantha milk, which first appeared in Episode IV (and tasted pretty awful in real life, according to Mark Hamill)?", "answer": " Blue"}
{"question": "Which Australian actor played Owen Lars a.k.a. Uncle Owen in Episodes II & III?", "answer": " Joel Edgerton"}
{"question": "At the beginning of \u201cSolo: A Star Wars Story,\u201d Han Solo enlists in the Imperial version of what branch of the Armed Forces?", "answer": " Imperial Navy"}
{"question": "Which film in the Skywalker Saga was the first to gross over a billion dollars at the box office? (You can answer either with the film's title or the episode number)", "answer": " Star Wars: Episode I \u2013 The Phantom Menace"}
{"question": "After playing the character on \"The Mandalorian,\" what actress plays former Jedi Ahsoka Tano on the Disney+ series \"Ahsoka\"?", "answer": " Rosario Dawson"}
{"question": "Selling for over $200,000 at auction in March 2022, the most valuable Star Wars action figure of all time was a \u201crocket\u201d launcher version of which character?", "answer": " Boba Fett"}
{"question": "Who was in charge of the cinematography of the prequel trilogy of movies (episodes I-III) of the Skywalker saga?", "answer": " David Tattersall"}
{"question": "Who was the director for the final movie in the Skywalker Saga: Episode IX - The Rise of Skywalker?", "answer": " J. J. Abrams"}
{"question": "In \"Star Wars: The Last Jedi,\" what were the creatures that Finn and Rose rode to escape the fabulously wealthy gambling den on Canto Bight?", "answer": " Fathiers"}
{"question": "Before becoming Supreme Chancellor (and then Emperor), Sheev Palpatine was a Galactic Senator from what world, the same as Padme Amidala?", "answer": " Naboo"}
{"question": "What desert in Tunisia was a filming location for several \u201cStar Wars\u201d movies, specifically in the role of Tatooine and Matmata?", "answer": " Sahara"}
{"question": "To what sentient species do the Caretakers of Ahch-to, who tend to the ancient structures in the Jedi village in \"The Last Jedi,\" belong?", "answer": " Lanai"}
{"question": "Of the 11 feature-length, live-action Star Wars films released by Lucasfilm in theaters, only one does not have R2-D2 in the film. Which movie is this?", "answer": " Solo: A Star Wars Story"}
{"question": "What retired FIFA Women\u2019s World Cup champion goalkeeper for Team USA has a name made of words from the titles of two different \u201cStar Wars\u201d movies?", "answer": " Hope Solo"}
{"question": "The most expensive properties in the Phantom Menace edition of Monopoly are on what skysrcapery city planet?", "answer": " Coruscant"}
{"question": "There is a city floating in the upper atmosphere of Bespin, a city which serves a dual-purpose as both a gas mine and a luxury resort. What is the name of this city?", "answer": " Cloud City"}
{"question": "In \u201cStar Wars Episode VIII: The Last Jedi\u201d, what actress plays Vice-Admiral Amilyn Holdo, a Rebel officer who briefly takes over for Admiral Leia after Leia is exposed to space? She won a Best Supporting Actress Oscar for \u201cMarriage Story\u201d in 2020.", "answer": " Laura Dern"}
{"question": "What type of crystal is used in the Star Wars universe as the power source of a lightsaber? This same source was used to generate the power for the Death Star's superlaser.", "answer": " Kyber crystal"}
{"question": "What \u201cB\u201d Star Wars character is a childhood acquaintance of Luke Skywalker\u2019s who flies in his X-Wing Squadron at the end of \u201cEpisode IV: A New Hope?\u201d His name is the same as the last name of actor Jason who starred in \u201cAmerican Pie.\u201d", "answer": " Biggs Darklighter"}
{"question": "One of many other movies to reference \"Star Wars,\" what 1998 disaster film features Ben Affleck's character declaring, \"I'm Han and you're Chewbacca?\"", "answer": " Armageddon"}
{"question": "When it came out in 1980, critics gave it mixed reviews. At 94% positive in 2022, which Star Wars film currently has the highest rating on Rotten Tomatoes?", "answer": " The Empire Strikes Back"}
{"question": "What Vietnamese American actress rose to prominence playing Rose Tico in the \"Star Wars\" franchise, beginning with \"The Last Jedi\" in 2017?", "answer": " Kelly Marie Tran"}
{"question": "Which 2015 Star Wars movie directed by J.J. Abrams was the first film in the franchise that didn\u2019t have a video game tie-in when it came out? (Fun Fact: It did eventually get a video game\u2026but just the Lego version).", "answer": " The Force Awakens"}
{"question": "Which Kenyan-Mexican, Oscar-winning actress played Maz Kanata, who we first meet in \u201cThe Force Awakens\u201d (2015)?", "answer": " Lupita Nyong'o"}
{"question": "Also home to the planet covering Imperial City, on which planet is the Jedi Temple located?", "answer": " Coruscant"}
{"question": "In the final episode of the first season of \"The Mandalorian,\" a famous weapon is revealed when briefly seen in the hands of Moff Gideon. What is this weapon?", "answer": " The Darksaber"}
{"question": "Ahsoka Tano is the Padawan apprentice of what other character in the Star Wars franchise? Tano will be played by Rosario Dawson in the second season of The Mandalorian.", "answer": " Anakin Skywalker"}
{"question": "Which Star Wars movie was given the working title \u201cBlue Harvest: Horror Beyond Imagination\u201d to disguise it from fans and the press while in production?", "answer": " Return of the Jedi"}
{"question": "At the end of \"Star Wars: The Rise of Skywalker.\" Rey pulls out and activates her own lightsaber for the first time. What color is it?", "answer": " Yellow"}
{"question": "Not counting the special achievement award won for the movie\u2019s sound, how many competitive Oscars did Star Wars Episode IV (A New Hope) win at the 50th Academy Awards from its ten nominations?", "answer": " Six"}
{"question": "In Star Wars Episode VIII, what character joins Finn and BB-8 on Canto Bight as they search for the master codebreaker?", "answer": " Rose"}
{"question": "What is the name of the oceanic planet where cloning technology is developed, and the Clone Army is created and trained? Obi-Wan visits this planet during \"Attack of the Clones.\"", "answer": " Kamino"}
{"question": "After Muppets creator Jim Henson declined the opportunity from George Lucas, he recommended what colleague to accept the role of puppeteer and voice actor for the Jedi Master Yoda?", "answer": " Frank Oz"}
{"question": "In the Star Wars universe, most residents of the planet Shili, including Jedi Master Shaak Ti and Padawan Ahsoka Tano, are members of what sentient humanoid species?", "answer": " Togruta"}
{"question": "Rey, the scavenger-turned-Jedi in the Star Wars \"sequel\" trilogy, is first shown on what planet?", "answer": " Jakku"}
{"question": "Appearing in \"The Last Jedi,\" the character Slowen Lo is named for the song \"Slow and Low\" from the 1986 album \"Licensed to Ill\" by what hip-hop group?", "answer": " The Beastie Boys"}
{"question": "Twelve years after his character fell and died in Mount Doom in \u201cThe Lord of the Rings: The Return of the King,\" what actor voiced the First Order\u2019s Supreme Leader Snoke in the 2015 film \u201cStar Wars: The Force Awakens\u201d?", "answer": " Andy Serkis"}
{"question": "In 2016\u2019s \u201cRogue One\u201d, Felicity Jones played what character, the daughter of the designer of the Death Star who becomes a leader in the Rebel Alliance after being rescued from detention by the Empire?", "answer": " Jyn Erso"}
{"question": "What character is responsible for the death of Jabba the Hutt in Return of the Jedi?", "answer": " Leia"}
{"question": "The film Fanboys (2009) tells the tale of a group of friends who travel across the country to break into Skywalker Ranch and steal a copy of what Star Wars film before its release? Please give just the name, not the episode number, and no need to include the words \"Star Wars.\"", "answer": " The Phantom Menace"}
{"question": "What was Luke Skywalker's last name in the original script for \"Star Wars: A New Hope?\" The name went on to be used for a military base similar to the Death Star in \"Star Wars: The Force Awakens.\"", "answer": " Starkiller"}
{"question": "Which 2005 addition to the Star Wars movie universe was the first of the films to be entirely shot in a studio?", "answer": " Star Wars: Episode III - Revenge of the Sith"}
{"question": "At a running time of 2 hours 32 minutes, what is the longest movie of the nine-movie \u2018Skywalker Saga\u2019, made up of the prequel, original and sequel trilogies?", "answer": " The Last Jedi"}
{"question": "At the start of 2015\u2019s \u201cThe Force Awakens,\u201d Finn had defected from his post as a stormtrooper in which faction?", "answer": " First Order"}
{"question": "Who is the only actor to have appeared in all the Star Wars films? In \"Solo: A Star Wars Story\" he plays a character named \"Tak,\" which is different from the character he normally plays in the films.", "answer": " Anthony Daniels"}
{"question": "Of the last three movies in the main storyline, \"The Force Awakens\" had the most Academy Award nominations, exactly half the number gotten by \"A New Hope.\". How many did \"The Force Awakens\" have?", "answer": " 5"}
{"question": "In what African nation were the scenes set on the planet Tattooine filmed (in a city called Tataouine, no less)?", "answer": " Tunisia"}
{"question": "Having a birthday on May 14, in which year was Star Wars creator George Lucas born? Three years either way accepted", "answer": " 1944"}
{"question": "What Star Wars film was a financial flop, losing (after production and marketing costs) a staggering $76.9 million?", "answer": " Solo: A Star Wars Story"}
{"question": "The music for the cantina scene in \"A New Hope\" was written by John Williams, but the music for the cantina scene in \"The Force Awakens\" (where Rey, Finn, Han, and Chewie go to Maz Kanata's watering hole) was co-written by director J.J. Abrams and what multiple Tony-award winning composer?", "answer": " Lin-Manuel Miranda"}
{"question": "On what planet, where the boundary between life and death is unusually thin, was Palpatine resurrected\u2014and later defeated\u2014in \"Star Wars: The Rise of Skywalker\"?", "answer": " Exegol"}
{"question": "For the planet Crait in \"The Last Jedi,\" filming was done at Salar de Uyuni, the world\u2019s largest salt flat. This real-life place is found in what South American nation?", "answer": " Bolivia"}
{"question": "What is the name of the horned, clawed white-furred species of snow monster found on the icy planet that was home to the Rebel Alliance's temporary Echo Base in \"The Empire Strikes Back\"?", "answer": " Wampas"}
{"question": "What Asian-American actress rose to prominence after playing the character of Rose Tico in \"The Last Jedi\" and \"The Rise of Skywalker?\"", "answer": " Kelly Marie Tran"}
{"question": "The planet Alderaan is well known to \u201cStar Wars\u201d fans for being the home of Bail Organa and what adopted daughter of his, who would rise above her royal ranks to become in essence the leader of the Rebel Alliance?", "answer": " Leia Organa"}
{"question": "Who was the senator from Naboo when Amidala was queen in \"Star War: Episode 1?\"", "answer": " Palpatine"}
{"question": "The exterior scenes from the planet of Hoth in \"The Empire Strikes Back\" were filmed on the Hardangerj\u00f8kulen glacier, located in what country?", "answer": " Norway"}
{"question": "In \"The Phantom Menace,\" Shmi and Anakin Skywalker are both slaves of what Todarian owner of a second-hand goods store on Tatooine?", "answer": " Watto"}
{"question": "Killed by Tusken Raiders on her home planet of Tatooine during \"Attack of the Clones,\" what was the first name of Annakin's mother?", "answer": " Shmi"}
{"question": "What actor was the only performer to earn an acting nomination for an Oscar in a Star Wars film? Note: we are looking for the actor, not the character.", "answer": " Alec Guinness"}
{"question": "What popular Star Wars side character made his first appearance in an animated segment during the \u201cStar Wars Holiday Special\u201d (1980), saving Luke Skywalker and others from a giant monster? He was born on the planet Kamino.", "answer": " Boba Fett"}
{"question": "Which Star Wars villain was originally played by Declan Mulholland in A New Hope, before the scene was cut and the character completely reimagined?", "answer": " Jabba the Hutt"}
{"question": "What is the name of the character played by Laura Dern in The Last Jedi whose namesake \"manouevre\" is essentially kamikaze attack done at lightspeed?", "answer": " Amilyn Holdo"}
{"question": "What sinister Dug and Pod Racing champion was bested by a young Anakin in Star Wars Episode I: The Phantom Menace?", "answer": " Sebulba"}
{"question": "Already familiar with marshaling from \"Justified\" and \"Fargo\" what actor played pseudo-law dude Cobb Vanth on \"The Mandalorian\" episode, \"The Marshal\"?", "answer": " Timothy Olyphant"}
{"question": "To make the TIE Fighter sound extra terrifying, legendary sound designer Ben Burtt combined the sound of cars on wet pavement with the sound of what formidable animal?", "answer": " Elephant"}
{"question": "A kerfuffle over the Darksaber and control of Mandalore sparked what Imperial genocide with a name similar to a horror franchise?", "answer": " The Great Purge"}
{"question": "What was the original title of Return of the Jedi? This title was used in a teaser trailer in 1982, as well as promotional posters, until George Lucas changed his mind.", "answer": " Revenge of the Jedi"}
{"question": "Which 2019 Star Wars sequel directed by J.J. Abrams centered on the epic showdown between the Resistance and Kylo Ren, and starred Carrie Fisher, Mark Hamill, Adam Driver, and Daisy Ridley?", "answer": " Star Wars: The Rise of Skywalker"}
{"question": "Of the nine movies in Star Wars' Skywalker Saga, how many were directed by George Lucas?", "answer": " 4 (Episodes I - IV)"}
{"question": "In the expanded universe its species is identified as being an Exogorth, but in \"Star Wars: Episode V - The Empire Strikes Back\" what alliterative name is given to the gigantic-toothed gastropod living in the asteroid which the Millennium Falcon seeks refuge in?", "answer": " Space Slug"}
{"question": "Before making \"A New Hope,\" George Lucas had sought to license the rights to a pulp-hero with a two-word name. This \"speedy\" hero's story eventually inspired many elements of the first Star Wars film. Who is this hero?", "answer": " Flash Gordon"}
{"question": "2021 saw the release of a Lego Star Wars app on Apple Arcade, featuring PvP fights between live players, with what \u201cB\u201d name? The name reminds fans of famous moments on Hoth, Naboo, and Yavin.", "answer": " Lego Star Wars Battles"}
{"question": "What two-word name is given to the cantina on Tatooine where Luke Skywalker and Obi-Wan Kenobi first encounter Han Solo? It\u2019s a hangout for a lot of seedy alien criminal types.", "answer": " Mos Eisley Cantina"}
{"question": "Aurebesh is the writing system used to represent what spoken-word language that is the most commonly referenced language in the \u201cStar Wars\u201d films?", "answer": " Galactic Basic"}
{"question": "What is the name of the series of Star Wars video games that began on the Nintendo 64 console in 1998 as one of the first games for the console that supported \"Expansion Pak\" which enabled higher-quality graphics?", "answer": " Rogue Squadron"}
{"question": "In the movie \"Star Wars\", R2D2 claimed he was the property of Obi-Wan Kenobi but C3PO disagreed. Who did C3PO claim was their former master?", "answer": " Captain Antilles"}
{"question": "In \"Star Wars: Episode IV, A New Hope,\" what is the number of the cell block on the Death Star that Luke Skywalker claims to be transferring Chewbacca from? The number is a reference to an earlier George Lucas film, which was in turn an expanded version of a student film he made while at USC.", "answer": " 1138"}
{"question": "In this infamous 1978 \u201cStar Wars Holiday Special\u201d, Han Solo joins Chewbacca on the Wookiee\u2019s home planet Kashyyyk to celebrate what holiday?", "answer": " Life Day"}
{"question": "What Star Wars mobile game allows you to collect characters from both the light and dark sides, such as Luke Skywalker and Darth Vader, then play them in RPG-style combat?", "answer": " Galaxy of Heroes"}
{"question": "What is the idyllic-sounding name of the starcruiser where you can have a two-night immersive experience at Walt Disney World Florida, including lightsaber lessons and a view of space from your cabin?", "answer": " Halcyon"}
{"question": "Featuring noted rogue Han Solo's proposal to Princess Leia, the 2022 latest Star Wars novel is called \"The Princess and the\" WHAT?", "answer": " Scoundrel"}
{"question": "Before he played young Anakin Skywalker in \u201cStar Wars Episode I: The Phantom Menace\u201d (1999), which actor got his big break playing Arnold Schwarzenegger\u2019s son in the holiday comedy, \u201cJingle All the Way\u201d (1996)?", "answer": " Jake Lloyd"}
{"question": "Though she gave it to Obi-Wan shortly before she died, Padm\u00e9 was buried with a good luck charm that had been made by Anakin. It was made from japor ivory wood, a type of wood from what planet?", "answer": " Tatooine"}
{"question": "In November 2022, Lucasfilm announced the cast for what religious-sounding upcoming Star Wars original TV series that will be set during the High Republic era?", "answer": " The Acolyte"}
{"question": "Neophyte Jedi Luke whines to Obi-Wan in \"A New Hope\" that what blocking structure keeps him from seeing during his Millennium Falcon lightsaber practice?", "answer": " Blast Shield"}
{"question": "Mostly known for playing Cliff Clavin on the sitcom \"Cheers,\" actor John Ratzenberger played Rebel Major Bren Derlin in which Star Wars film?", "answer": " The Empire Strikes Back"}
{"question": "What is the name of the large omnivorous cephalopods from the planet Vodran, having seven suckered tentacles, an eyestalk, a mouth of sharp teeth and several hearts?", "answer": " Dianoga"}
{"question": "What\u2019s the name of the tree-covered planet that Wookies call home?", "answer": " Kashyyyk"}
{"question": "With long limbs, lozenge-shaped furry bodies, and a name that contains lots of letters from the end of the alphabet, what species of Endor included Joh Yowza and Wam Lufba?", "answer": " Yuzzum"}
{"question": "Since it was released in November of 1976, \u201cStar Wars: From the Adventures of Luke Skywalker\u201d actually came before the first Star Wars film, which it was a tie-in for. What kind of media was it?", "answer": " Novel"}
{"question": "Parker Brothers released the first officially licensed Star Wars video game in 1982 on which console?", "answer": " Atari 2600"}
{"question": "What much-reviled \"Star Wars\" character is a Twi'lek who served for decades as majordomo and chief of staff to Jabba the Hutt?", "answer": " Bib Fortuna"}
{"question": "Which actor who starred as Han in 2018\u2019s \u201cSolo: A Star Wars Story\u201d has said he got his big break acting in a video for a friend\u2019s bat mitzvah that was subsequently watched by Steven Spielberg?", "answer": " Alden Ehrenreich"}
{"question": "What line of highly muscled heroes and villains was created by Mattel in 1979 to try and rival the popularity of Kenner's Star Wars action figures? Mattel introduced their backstory with a comic book, and made them the subject of an animated television series that ran from 1983 to 1985.", "answer": " Masters of the Universe"}
{"question": "What is Jedi Master Yoda's last name in the Star Wars franchise?", "answer": " He doesn't have one"}
{"question": "Grand Moff Tarkin, the commander of the Death Star and loyal advisor to Darth Vader in \"Star Wars: Episode IV\", was played by legendary British actor, probably otherwise best known for dueling with Christopher Lee in a series of Hammer horror films?", "answer": " Peter Cushing"}
{"question": "The iconic score for Star Wars Episode IV was recorded in 1977 by John Williams, and the Symphony Irchestra of which city?", "answer": " London"}
{"question": "A British prince and the First Son of the U.S. fall in love despite enthusiastically disagreeing on which \"Star Wars\" movie is the best, in what bestselling 2019 novel by Casey McQuiston?", "answer": " Red, White, & Royal Blue"}
{"question": "What \u201cPulp Fiction\u201d actor was George Lucas\u2019 second choice to play Han Solo and would have taken the role had Harrison Ford declined it?", "answer": " Christopher Walken"}
{"question": "What independent organic chocolate producer was purchased by Hershey's in 2006? The brand name sounds like a planet in the Star Wars universe, although it really comes from a Sanskrit word meaning \"hemispherical dome.\"", "answer": " Dagoba"}
{"question": "The language spoken by the Ewoks is a combination of two real-life languages. Name either one!", "answer": " Tibetan and Nepalese"}
{"question": "What was the very first Star Wars movie released?", "answer": "Star Wars: A New Hope (1977)"}
{"question": "Who directed The Empire Strikes Back?", "answer": "Irvin Kershner"}
{"question": "What is the subtitle of Episode VI?", "answer": "Return of the Jedi"}
{"question": "Who says, \u201cI\u2019ve got a bad feeling about this\u201d first in the original trilogy?", "answer": "Luke Skywalker"}
{"question": "What is the name of the planet destroyed by the Death Star in A New Hope?", "answer": "Alderaan"}
{"question": "What color is Mace Windu\u2019s lightsaber?", "answer": "Purple"}
{"question": "Who played Princess Leia?", "answer": "Carrie Fisher"}
{"question": "What species is Chewbacca?", "answer": "Wookiee"}
{"question": "What is the Sith rule of two?", "answer": "Always two there are, no more, no less. A master and an apprentice."}
{"question": "What year was The Phantom Menace released?", "answer": "1999"}
{"question": "Which actor portrayed Anakin Skywalker in the prequel trilogy?", "answer": "Hayden Christensen"}
{"question": "Who is revealed to be Luke Skywalker\u2019s father?", "answer": "Darth Vader"}
{"question": "What is the name of Han Solo\u2019s ship?", "answer": "Millennium Falcon"}
{"question": "In The Force Awakens, who is the scavenger from Jakku?", "answer": "Rey"}
{"question": "What is Finn\u2019s stormtrooper designation?", "answer": "FN-2187"}
{"question": "Who is the leader of the First Order?", "answer": "Supreme Leader Snoke"}
{"question": "What color is Yoda\u2019s lightsaber in Attack of the Clones?", "answer": "Green"}
{"question": "What is Kylo Ren\u2019s real name?", "answer": "Ben Solo"}
{"question": "What is the opening line of the Star Wars crawl in A New Hope?", "answer": "\u201cIt is a period of civil war.\u201d"}
{"question": "How many parsecs did Han Solo claim the Millennium Falcon made the Kessel Run in?", "answer": "Less than twelve"}
{"question": "What planet is Obi-Wan Kenobi watching over Luke Skywalker on?", "answer": "Tatooine"}
{"question": "Who killed Jabba the Hutt?", "answer": "Princess Leia"}
{"question": "What is the name of the battle station in A New Hope?", "answer": "The Death Star"}
{"question": "Who says, \u201cDo or do not, there is no try\u201d?", "answer": "Yoda"}
{"question": "What does BB-8\u2019s name refer to?", "answer": "His round shape resembling two B\u2019s and an 8"}
{"question": "Which bounty hunter captures Han Solo in The Empire Strikes Back?", "answer": "Boba Fett"}
{"question": "Who plays Lando Calrissian in Solo: A Star Wars Story?", "answer": "Donald Glover"}
{"question": "Who is Palpatine\u2019s master?", "answer": "Darth Plagueis"}
{"question": "What is the name of Luke\u2019s aunt?", "answer": "Aunt Beru"}
{"question": "Who says, \u201cI find your lack of faith disturbing\u201d?", "answer": "Darth Vader"}
{"question": "What kind of droid is R2-D2?", "answer": "Astromech droid"}
{"question": "What is the name of Poe Dameron\u2019s X-Wing?", "answer": "Black One"}
{"question": "Who is the young boy who helps Qui-Gon Jinn and Obi-Wan in The Phantom Menace?", "answer": "Anakin Skywalker"}
{"question": "What planet does the final battle take place on in The Rise of Skywalker?", "answer": "Exegol"}
{"question": "Who trains Rey in The Last Jedi?", "answer": "Luke Skywalker"}
{"question": "What is the name of the Ewok that befriends Princess Leia?", "answer": "Wicket"}
{"question": "What language do Wookiees speak?", "answer": "Shyriiwook"}
{"question": "What is the title of Episode II?", "answer": "Attack of the Clones"}
{"question": "Who killed Qui-Gon Jinn?", "answer": "Darth Maul"}
{"question": "What is the name of the clone trooper who killed Jedi Master Plo Koon during Order 66?", "answer": "Clone Commander Wolffe"}
{"question": "What species is Admiral Ackbar?", "answer": "Mon Calamari"}
{"question": "Who portrayed Obi-Wan Kenobi in the original trilogy?", "answer": "Alec Guinness"}
{"question": "What is the name of the resistance pilot played by Greg Grunberg in The Force Awakens?", "answer": "Snap Wexley"}
{"question": "Which character is known for saying, \u201cSo this is how liberty dies\u2014with thunderous applause\u201d?", "answer": "Padm\u00e9 Amidala"}
{"question": "What planet does Rey find Luke Skywalker on at the end of The Force Awakens?", "answer": "Ahch-To"}
{"question": "Who plays the voice of Darth Vader?", "answer": "James Earl Jones"}
{"question": "What is the name of the winged podracer that Anakin Skywalker competes with in The Phantom Menace?", "answer": "Sebulba"}
{"question": "What is the name of the droid who serves as a translator for Jabba the Hutt?", "answer": "EV-9D9"}
{"question": "Who is revealed to be the true mastermind behind the creation of the clone army in Attack of the Clones?", "answer": "Darth Sidious"}
{"question": "What is the name of the alien species Greedo belongs to?", "answer": "Rodian"}
{"question": "Which Star Wars movie features the battle of Endor?", "answer": "Return of the Jedi"}
{"question": "Who destroys the second Death Star?", "answer": "Lando Calrissian and Nien Nunb"}
{"question": "What creature attacks Luke in the Wampa cave?", "answer": "A Wampa"}
{"question": "Who takes command of the Rebel fleet after Admiral Ackbar\u2019s death in The Last Jedi?", "answer": "Vice Admiral Holdo"}
{"question": "What type of creature is the \u201cSarlacc\u201d?", "answer": "A giant carnivorous creature in the Great Pit of Carkoon"}
{"question": "What is the nickname for the group of elite First Order stormtroopers commanded by Kylo Ren?", "answer": "The Knights of Ren"}
{"question": "Who was Count Dooku\u2019s Padawan before he turned to the Dark Side?", "answer": "Qui-Gon Jinn"}
{"question": "What is the name of the Rebel pilot who survives the first Death Star attack in A New Hope?", "answer": "Wedge Antilles"}
{"question": "What is the name of the assassin sent to kill Padm\u00e9 Amidala in Attack of the Clones?", "answer": "Zam Wesell"}
{"question": "What is the name of the ship Rey inherits from Han Solo?", "answer": "Millennium Falcon"}
{"question": "What weapon does the Mandalorian wield as his signature tool?", "answer": "Amban phase-pulse blaster"}
{"question": "In which Star Wars film does Yoda fight Count Dooku?", "answer": "Attack of the Clones"}
{"question": "What was Darth Vader\u2019s original name?", "answer": "Anakin Skywalker"}
{"question": "Who is the villainous Sith Lord in The Rise of Skywalker?", "answer": "Emperor Palpatine (as Darth Sidious)"}
{"question": "What do Ewoks live in?", "answer": "Tree villages on Endor"}
{"question": "Who is the pilot of the Ghost in Star Wars: Rebels?", "answer": "Hera Syndulla"}
{"question": "What is the name of Ahsoka Tano\u2019s mentor?", "answer": "Anakin Skywalker"}
{"question": "What is the name of the Mandalorian artifact sought by many clans?", "answer": "The Darksaber"}
{"question": "Who is the leader of the Separatist droid army?", "answer": "General Grievous"}
{"question": "What is the name of Darth Maul\u2019s brother?", "answer": "Savage Opress"}
{"question": "What type of droid is Chopper from Star Wars: Rebels?", "answer": "C1-series astromech"}
{"question": "Who is the bounty hunter that captures Ahsoka Tano in The Clone Wars?", "answer": "Cad Bane"}
{"question": "What is the name of the clone with the number CT-7567?", "answer": "Captain Rex"}
{"question": "Who trained Count Dooku in the ways of the Force?", "answer": "Yoda"}
{"question": "What planet is home to the Twi\u2019leks?", "answer": "Ryloth"}
{"question": "Who is the ruler of Mandalore during The Clone Wars?", "answer": "Duchess Satine Kryze"}
{"question": "What is the name of the secret Jedi Temple Ahsoka visits in Rebels?", "answer": "The Lothal Temple"}
{"question": "Who leads the Nightsisters of Dathomir?", "answer": "Mother Talzin"}
{"question": "What is the name of the planet that serves as the main Clone Wars base for the Republic?", "answer": "Kamino"}
{"question": "Who fights Maul in the final season of The Clone Wars?", "answer": "Ahsoka Tano"}
{"question": "What is the name of the clone who becomes a Rebel leader in Rebels?", "answer": "Captain Rex"}
{"question": "Who is Ezra Bridger\u2019s first mentor in Rebels?", "answer": "Kanan Jarrus"}
{"question": "What is the name of the creature that helps Kanan connect with the Force?", "answer": "The Loth-Wolf"}
{"question": "Who is the Mandalorian warrior that works with Ahsoka in Rebels?", "answer": "Sabine Wren"}
{"question": "What is the name of the capital city of Mandalore?", "answer": "Sundari"}
{"question": "What is the Jedi term for a Force-sensitive child?", "answer": "Force-sensitive youngling"}
{"question": "What is the name of Han Solo and Leia\u2019s son in the Legends timeline?", "answer": "Jacen Solo"}
{"question": "What is the title of the book trilogy written by Timothy Zahn?", "answer": "The Thrawn Trilogy"}
{"question": "Who is the first Emperor of the Sith Empire?", "answer": "Exar Kun"}
{"question": "What planet does Mara Jade come from?", "answer": "Coruscant"}
{"question": "What is the name of the Sith homeworld in Legends?", "answer": "Korriban"}
{"question": "What is the name of Luke Skywalker\u2019s wife in Legends?", "answer": "Mara Jade"}
{"question": "Who is the Jedi Grandmaster during the Old Republic era?", "answer": "Nomi Sunrider"}
{"question": "What is the name of the Sith Lord known for using the Force to create life?", "answer": "Darth Plagueis"}
{"question": "What ancient Sith artifact causes chaos in the New Jedi Order?", "answer": "The Holocron of Heresies"}
{"question": "Who destroys the first Death Star in the Legends timeline?", "answer": "Jek Porkins (alternate reality story)"}
{"question": "In \u201cThe Empire Strikes Back,\u201d what does Yoda say when Luke first arrives at his hut?", "answer": " \u201cWhat know you of ready? For eight hundred years have I trained Jedi.\u201d"}
{"question": "Name three characters other than Anakin Skywalker who have been referred to as \u201cThe Chosen One\u201d in Star Wars lore.", "answer": " Anakin Skywalker, Rey (in the sequel trilogy), and Revan (in Star Wars: Legends)."}
{"question": "What is the name of the ancient Sith Lord who is considered the creator of the Rule of Two?", "answer": " Darth Bane."}
{"question": "In \u201cReturn of the Jedi,\u201d what is the name of the creature in the pit beneath Jabba\u2019s throne that Luke battles?", "answer": " Rancor."}
{"question": "Who was the original voice actor for Yoda in \u201cThe Empire Strikes Back\u201d before Frank Oz took over the role?", "answer": " John Lithgow."}
{"question": "What is the name of the droid that serves as a translator for Watto, the junk dealer in \u201cThe Phantom Menace\u201d?", "answer": " TC-14."}
{"question": "In \u201cA New Hope,\u201d what does Han Solo claim is the special modification he made to the Millennium Falcon?", "answer": " \u201cIt\u2019s the ship that made the Kessel Run in less than twelve parsecs.\u201d"}
{"question": "What is the name of the creature that attacks Luke Skywalker on the ice planet Hoth in \u201cThe Empire Strikes Back\u201d?", "answer": " Wampa."}
{"question": "In \u201cThe Force Awakens,\u201d what is the name of the scavenger who trades portions for valuable scraps on Jakku?", "answer": " Unkar Plutt."}
{"question": "What is the full name of the bounty hunter known as \u201cBoba Fett\u201d?", "answer": " Boba Fett\u2019s full name is CT-7567, a clone of Jango Fett, with the nickname \u201cBoba.\u201d"}
{"question": "What planet does Anakin Skywalker, later known as Darth Vader, originate from?", "answer": " Tatooine."}
{"question": "Where was Princess Leia Organa adopted and raised?", "answer": " Alderaan."}
{"question": "What is the species of Yoda, the wise and powerful Jedi Master?", "answer": " Unknown (never revealed in the Star Wars canon)."}
{"question": "Where was Han Solo born and raised?", "answer": " Corellia."}
{"question": "What was the birth name of the Sith Lord who becomes Emperor Palpatine?", "answer": " Sheev Palpatine."}
{"question": "Which planet is Chewbacca from?", "answer": " Kashyyyk."}
{"question": "What is the homeworld of Lando Calrissian, the smooth-talking gambler and owner of the Millennium Falcon?", "answer": " Socorro."}
{"question": "From which planet does Mace Windu, a high-ranking Jedi Master, hail?", "answer": " Haruun Kal."}
{"question": "What is the species of the bounty hunter Boba Fett?", "answer": " Mandalorian."}
{"question": "Before becoming a Jedi, where was Obi-Wan Kenobi originally from?", "answer": " Stewjon (non-canonical)."}
{"question": "What is the name of the desert planet where Rey, the main protagonist in the sequel trilogy, grows up?", "answer": " Jakku."}
{"question": "What is the species of the Wookiee who co-pilots the Millennium Falcon with Han Solo?", "answer": " Wookiee."}
{"question": "Where was Kylo Ren, also known as Ben Solo, trained in the ways of the Force?", "answer": " Luke Skywalker\u2019s Jedi Temple."}
{"question": "What planet is home to the Togruta species, from which Ahsoka Tano originates?", "answer": " Shili."}
{"question": "Before joining the Rebellion, where was Cassian Andor, a character from \u201cRogue One,\u201d originally from?", "answer": " Fest."}
{"question": "What is the species of the diminutive green-skinned Jedi Master, Yaddle?", "answer": " Unknown (never revealed in the Star Wars canon)."}
{"question": "Where was Padm\u00e9 Amidala, the former Queen and later Senator, born?", "answer": " Naboo."}
{"question": "What is the icy planet where the Rebel Alliance establishes its Echo Base in \u201cThe Empire Strikes Back\u201d?", "answer": " Hoth."}
{"question": "Which gas giant is the location of Cloud City, a mining colony run by Lando Calrissian?", "answer": " Bespin."}
{"question": "What is the name of the desert planet that serves as the backdrop for much of \u201cThe Phantom Menace\u201d?", "answer": " Tatooine."}
{"question": "Where is the forest moon of Endor located?", "answer": " Endor is a gas giant, and the forest moon orbits it."}
{"question": "Which planet is home to the capital city of the Galactic Republic and later the Galactic Empire?", "answer": " Coruscant."}
{"question": "What is the name of the oceanic planet where the Battle of Naboo takes place in \u201cThe Phantom Menace\u201d?", "answer": " Mon Cala."}
{"question": "Where is the Jedi Temple located before its destruction in \u201cRevenge of the Sith\u201d?", "answer": " Coruscant."}
{"question": "What is the remote, swampy planet where Yoda goes into exile after the fall of the Jedi?", "answer": " Dagobah."}
{"question": "Which planet is the primary setting for the final battle between the Resistance and the First Order in \u201cThe Rise of Skywalker\u201d?", "answer": " Exegol."}
{"question": "What is the forested moon where the Ewoks help the Rebel Alliance defeat the Empire in \u201cReturn of the Jedi\u201d?", "answer": " Endor."}
{"question": "Where does Rey first meet Luke Skywalker at the end of \u201cThe Force Awakens\u201d?", "answer": " Ahch-To."}
{"question": "Which planet is the homeworld of the Kaminoans, known for their cloning technology?", "answer": " Kamino."}
{"question": "Where does the majority of the action take place in \u201cRogue One: A Star Wars Story\u201d?", "answer": " Scarif."}
{"question": "What is the name of the city-planet destroyed by the Death Star in \u201cA New Hope\u201d?", "answer": " Alderaan."}
{"question": "Where does the Rebel Alliance set up its base in \u201cReturn of the Jedi\u201d before the Battle of Endor?", "answer": " Sullust."}
{"question": "In \u201cThe Last Jedi,\u201d what is the mineral-rich planet that the Resistance seeks refuge on?", "answer": " Crait."}
{"question": "Where is the remote desert planet where Rey begins her journey in \u201cThe Force Awakens\u201d?", "answer": " Jakku."}
{"question": "What is the color of Mace Windu\u2019s lightsaber?", "answer": " Purple."}
{"question": "Which Jedi Master uses a double-bladed lightsaber in \u201cThe Phantom Menace\u201d?", "answer": " Qui-Gon Jinn."}
{"question": "What is the traditional color of a Sith lightsaber?", "answer": " Red."}
{"question": "Which iconic Jedi weapon is passed down to Luke Skywalker by Obi-Wan Kenobi?", "answer": " Anakin Skywalker\u2019s lightsaber."}
{"question": "What is the name of the lightsaber combat style developed by Mace Windu, known for channeling the dark side in a controlled manner?", "answer": " Vaapad."}
{"question": "Who is the only Jedi known to have mastered the power of battle meditation, as mentioned in Star Wars lore?", "answer": " Bastila Shan."}
{"question": "What is the name of the ancient, extinct order of Force-sensitive beings who wielded white lightsabers?", "answer": " The Guardians of the Kyber Crystals."}
{"question": "Which Sith Lord created the Rule of Two, mandating that there can only be two Sith at a time?", "answer": " Darth Bane."}
{"question": "What is the name of the lightsaber combat style that focuses on defense and conserving energy?", "answer": " Soresu."}
{"question": "Who is the only Jedi in the Star Wars films known to use a yellow-bladed lightsaber?", "answer": " Ahsoka Tano."}
{"question": "Which Jedi had a unique, curved-hilt lightsaber and served as a Jedi Temple Guard?", "answer": " Cin Drallig."}
{"question": "What is the name of the Sith apprentice who wielded two red lightsabers in \u201cStar Wars: The Clone Wars\u201d animated series?", "answer": " Asajj Ventress."}
{"question": "Who is the Sith Lord who turns Anakin Skywalker to the dark side of the Force?", "answer": " Darth Sidious (Emperor Palpatine)."}
{"question": "What lightsaber form did Anakin Skywalker primarily use before turning to the dark side?", "answer": " Form V: Shien/Djem So."}
{"question": "What is the name of the Jedi who trained both Obi-Wan Kenobi and Anakin Skywalker?", "answer": " Qui-Gon Jinn."}
{"question": "Which Sith Lord wields a double-bladed spinning lightsaber in \u201cThe Phantom Menace\u201d?", "answer": " Darth Maul."}
{"question": "What is the primary lightsaber form associated with Count Dooku?", "answer": " Form II: Makashi."}
{"question": "What is the name of Han Solo\u2019s iconic spaceship?", "answer": " Millennium Falcon."}
{"question": "Which class of starfighter does Luke Skywalker pilot during the Battle of Yavin in \u201cA New Hope\u201d?", "answer": " X-wing."}
{"question": "What type of vehicle does Rey use to traverse the deserts of Jakku in \u201cThe Force Awakens\u201d?", "answer": " Speeder (Rey\u2019s Speeder)."}
{"question": "What is the capital ship of the Rebel Alliance and later the New Republic?", "answer": " Mon Calamari Star Cruiser (e.g., Home One)."}
{"question": "What is the name of the podracer Anakin Skywalker pilots in \u201cThe Phantom Menace\u201d?", "answer": " Anakin\u2019s Podracer (or Boonta Eve Classic Podracer)."}
{"question": "Which bounty hunter ship is known for its distinctive shape and is piloted by Boba Fett?", "answer": " Slave I."}
{"question": "What is the name of the Imperial walker vehicles used by the Empire on Hoth in \u201cThe Empire Strikes Back\u201d?", "answer": " AT-AT (All Terrain Armored Transport)."}
{"question": "In \u201cThe Clone Wars\u201d animated series, what type of starfighter is primarily used by the Republic?", "answer": " ARC-170."}
{"question": "What is the name of the massive starship that serves as the First Order\u2019s mobile capital in \u201cThe Last Jedi\u201d?", "answer": " Supremacy."}
{"question": "Which class of starfighter is commonly used by the Empire, featuring a distinct tri-wing design?", "answer": " TIE Fighter."}
{"question": "What is the Corellian freighter ship that transports the Death Star plans in \u201cRogue One\u201d?", "answer": " Profundity (Admiral Raddus\u2019s ship)."}
{"question": "What type of starfighter is commonly associated with the Clone Wars era and features a twin-engine design?", "answer": " V-wing."}
{"question": "What is the name of the podracer owned by Sebulba in \u201cThe Phantom Menace\u201d?", "answer": " Sebulba\u2019s Podracer."}
{"question": "What is the Resistance\u2019s primary starfighter in \u201cThe Force Awakens\u201d?", "answer": " T-70 X-wing."}
{"question": "What is the name of the small, fast ship used by the Rebel Alliance and the Resistance for hit-and-run missions?", "answer": " A-wing."}
{"question": "In \u201cReturn of the Jedi,\u201d what type of ship is used to transport Jabba the Hutt\u2019s sail barge?", "answer": " Khetanna (a luxury sail barge)."}
{"question": "What is the name of the Imperial transport shuttle that was used to ferry troops and cargo?", "answer": " Lambda-class T-4a shuttle."}
{"question": "Finish the famous line: \u201cMay the Force be\u2026\u201d", "answer": " \u201c\u2026with you.\u201d"}
{"question": "Who says, \u201cI find your lack of faith disturbing\u201d?", "answer": " Darth Vader."}
{"question": "In \u201cThe Empire Strikes Back,\u201d what does Yoda say about the future?", "answer": " \u201cDifficult to see. Always in motion is the future.\u201d"}
{"question": "Who declares, \u201cI\u2019ve got a bad feeling about this\u201d in every main Star Wars movie?", "answer": " Various characters, but the line is said by Han Solo in \u201cThe Force Awakens.\u201d"}
{"question": "What does Obi-Wan Kenobi tell Anakin Skywalker after defeating him in \u201cRevenge of the Sith\u201d?", "answer": " \u201cYou were the chosen one! It was said that you would destroy the Sith, not join them.\u201d"}
{"question": "Complete the line: \u201cHelp me, Obi-Wan Kenobi, you\u2019re my only\u2026\u201d", "answer": " \u201c\u2026hope.\u201d"}
{"question": "Who tells Luke Skywalker, \u201cDo or do not, there is no try\u201d?", "answer": " Yoda."}
{"question": "What does Princess Leia say to Han Solo before he is frozen in carbonite?", "answer": " \u201cI love you.\u201d (Han Solo\u2019s response: \u201cI know.\u201d)"}
{"question": "What is the last line of \u201cThe Rise of Skywalker\u201d?", "answer": " \u201cAnd in the end, the love you take is equal to the love you make.\u201d"}
{"question": "Who says, \u201cChewie, we\u2019re home\u201d in \u201cThe Force Awakens\u201d?", "answer": " Han Solo."}
{"question": "Complete the line: \u201cThe Force will be with you, always.\u201d", "answer": " Obi-Wan Kenobi."}
{"question": "Who famously says, \u201cIt\u2019s a trap!\u201d?", "answer": " Admiral Ackbar."}
{"question": "What does Emperor Palpatine say when using his Sith lightning against Mace Windu?", "answer": " \u201cUnlimited power!\u201d"}
{"question": "Who declares, \u201cI am your father\u201d?", "answer": " Darth Vader."}
{"question": "Finish the line from \u201cThe Phantom Menace\u201d: \u201cFear is the path to the dark side\u2026\u201d", "answer": " \u201c\u2026Fear leads to anger, anger leads to hate, hate leads to suffering.\u201d"}
{"question": "What does Kylo Ren say to Rey in \u201cThe Last Jedi\u201d?", "answer": " \u201cYou\u2019re nothing. But not to me.\u201d"}
{"question": "Who tells Rey, \u201cThe belonging you seek is not behind you; it is ahead\u201d?", "answer": " Maz Kanata."}
{"question": "What event marked the beginning of the Clone Wars?", "answer": " The Battle of Geonosis."}
{"question": "What ancient Sith species played a significant role in shaping early Sith history?", "answer": " Sith Purebloods."}
{"question": "What is the name of the Sith Lord who orchestrated the blockade of Naboo in \u201cThe Phantom Menace\u201d?", "answer": " Darth Sidious (Emperor Palpatine)."}
{"question": "Which event led to the establishment of the Galactic Republic?", "answer": " The Ruusan Reformation."}
{"question": "What war was fought between the Galactic Republic and the Sith Empire thousands of years before the events of the films?", "answer": " The Great Galactic War."}
{"question": "What were the ancient guardians of the Sith tombs on Korriban known as?", "answer": " Sithspawn."}
{"question": "Which organization was responsible for constructing the Death Star in \u201cA New Hope\u201d?", "answer": " The Galactic Empire."}
{"question": "What treaty marked the end of the Great Hyperspace War between the Sith Empire and the Galactic Republic?", "answer": " Treaty of Coruscant."}
{"question": "What event resulted in the destruction of Alderaan in \u201cA New Hope\u201d?", "answer": " The Death Star\u2019s superlaser."}
{"question": "What is the name of the ancient Sith Lord who created the Rule of Two?", "answer": " Darth Bane."}
{"question": "What group was responsible for the creation of the Clone Army?", "answer": " The Sith (specifically, Darth Sidious)."}
{"question": "What was the purpose of the Jedi Council during the High Republic era?", "answer": " To maintain peace and justice in the galaxy."}
{"question": "Who was the Supreme Chancellor of the Galactic Republic at the beginning of \u201cThe Phantom Menace\u201d?", "answer": " Finis Valorum."}
{"question": "What was the name of the ancient Sith Lord who was awakened in \u201cThe Rise of Skywalker\u201d?", "answer": " Darth Sidious (Emperor Palpatine)."}
{"question": "What event led to the rise of the Galactic Empire and the fall of the Galactic Republic?", "answer": " Order 66 (the execution of Jedi by the Clone Troopers)."}
{"question": "What was the purpose of the Separatist Alliance in the Clone Wars?", "answer": " To break away from the Galactic Republic."}
{"question": "What ancient Jedi prophecy foretold the rise of a chosen one who would bring balance to the Force?", "answer": " The Prophecy of the Chosen One."}
{"question": "What species is Chewbacca?", "answer": " Wookiee."}
{"question": "What are the small, green-skinned, and wise inhabitants of the planet Dagobah?", "answer": " Yoda\u2019s species (species name not revealed)."}
{"question": "What are the tall, fur-covered creatures that live on the forest moon of Endor?", "answer": " Ewoks."}
{"question": "What species is known for its adeptness in podracing, and Anakin Skywalker is a notable member?", "answer": " Dug."}
{"question": "What is the name of the species that Han Solo belongs to?", "answer": " Human (Corellian)."}
{"question": "Which species is known for its elaborate face tattoos and aggressive behavior, exemplified by Darth Maul?", "answer": " Dathomirian Zabrak."}
{"question": "What are the tall, thin, and blue-skinned inhabitants of the desert planet Twi\u2019lek?", "answer": " Twi\u2019lek."}
{"question": "Which species has a distinctive head-tail called lekku, as seen on Aayla Secura?", "answer": " Togruta."}
{"question": "What insectoid species is known for its hives and connection to the Geonosians?", "answer": " Verpine."}
{"question": "What is the name of the species that Yaddle, a member of the Jedi Council, belongs to?", "answer": " Yoda\u2019s species (species name not revealed)."}
{"question": "Which species is known for its aquatic nature and is native to the Mon Cala planet?", "answer": " Mon Calamari."}
{"question": "What reptilian species is known for its bounty hunting skills, exemplified by Bossk?", "answer": " Trandoshan."}
{"question": "Which species is known for its tall, slender, and humanoid appearance with distinctive face tendrils?", "answer": " Nautolan."}
{"question": "What species is the bounty hunter IG-88?", "answer": " IG-series assassin droid (not organic)."}
{"question": "What is the name of the diminutive green-skinned species that Yoda and Yaddle belong to?", "answer": " Yoda\u2019s species (species name not revealed)."}
{"question": "Which species is known for its large eyes, elongated heads, and expertise in podracing, as seen with Sebulba?", "answer": " Dug."}
{"question": "What is the name of the species that Jabba the Hutt belongs to?", "answer": " Hutt."}
{"question": "What is the name of the protocol droid fluent in over six million forms of communication, often seen with C-3PO?", "answer": " C-3PO."}
{"question": "Which astromech droid assists Anakin Skywalker and later Luke Skywalker in their adventures?", "answer": " R2-D2."}
{"question": "What type of droid is IG-88, known for its assassin capabilities?", "answer": " IG-series assassin droid."}
{"question": "What is the designation of the small, mouse-like droid that helps repair the Millennium Falcon in \u201cThe Empire Strikes Back\u201d?", "answer": " MSE-6-series repair droid (commonly called a mouse droid)."}
{"question": "What is the name of the droid that serves as a companion to Obi-Wan Kenobi in \u201cThe Clone Wars\u201d animated series?", "answer": " R4-P17."}
{"question": "What type of droid is BB-8, the spherical astromech in the sequel trilogy?", "answer": " BB unit."}
{"question": "What is the name of the droid that assists the Rebel Alliance in deciphering the Death Star plans in \u201cRogue One\u201d?", "answer": " K-2SO."}
{"question": "Which droid is a medical assistant to the Jedi and is seen in the prequel trilogy, particularly in \u201cThe Phantom Menace\u201d?", "answer": " 2-1B surgical droid."}
{"question": "What is the name of the astromech droid that accompanies Padm\u00e9 Amidala in \u201cThe Phantom Menace\u201d?", "answer": " R2-N2."}
{"question": "What type of droid is HK-47, known for its ruthless and humorous personality in the \u201cKnights of the Old Republic\u201d video game?", "answer": " Assassin droid."}
{"question": "What is the designation of the droid bounty hunter that confronts Han Solo and friends in \u201cThe Empire Strikes Back\u201d?", "answer": " 4-LOM."}
{"question": "What type of droid is Chopper, a cantankerous astromech featured in \u201cStar Wars Rebels\u201d?", "answer": " C1-series astromech droid."}
{"question": "Which droid is known for its spherical design and serves as a mobile interface in the Jedi Temple?", "answer": " Training Remote (Remote)."}
{"question": "What is the name of the droid character that speaks only in beeps and whistles and accompanies Finn and Rey in \u201cThe Force Awakens\u201d?", "answer": " BB-8."}
{"question": "What type of droids serve as the foot soldiers of the Separatist Alliance in the Clone Wars?", "answer": " Battle droids (B1-series and others)."}
{"question": "What is the designation of the silver protocol droid seen in Cloud City, translating for Lando Calrissian?", "answer": " TC-14."}
{"question": "What type of droid is commonly used by the Empire for torture and interrogation, as seen in \u201cA New Hope\u201d?", "answer": " IT-O Interrogator Droid."}
{"question": "What is the Jedi mind trick, and which character famously uses it in \u201cA New Hope\u201d?", "answer": " A technique to influence weak-minded individuals; Obi-Wan Kenobi uses it on stormtroopers."}
{"question": "Which Force power allows a user to sense the feelings and intentions of others?", "answer": " Force empathy."}
{"question": "What is the ability to see events from the past or future through the Force called?", "answer": " Force visions."}
{"question": "Who uses the Force power of Force choke as a display of dark side strength?", "answer": " Darth Vader."}
{"question": "What is the technique of absorbing or deflecting energy attacks with a lightsaber called?", "answer": " Tutaminis."}
{"question": "Which Jedi power enables enhanced physical abilities such as speed and agility?", "answer": " Force speed."}
{"question": "What is the Force power used to heal physical injuries or wounds?", "answer": " Force healing."}
{"question": "Who is known for using the Force power of Force lightning?", "answer": " Emperor Palpatine (Darth Sidious)."}
{"question": "What is the Jedi ability to influence the thoughts and feelings of others called?", "answer": " Battle meditation."}
{"question": "Which Force power allows a user to disappear or move instantly from one location to another?", "answer": " Force teleportation or Force flash."}
{"question": "Who uses the Jedi mind trick to free himself from captivity in Jabba the Hutt\u2019s palace?", "answer": " Luke Skywalker."}
{"question": "What Force power enables a Jedi to absorb and redirect blaster bolts?", "answer": " Force deflection."}
{"question": "Which Sith Lord is known for using the power of Essence Transfer to achieve immortality?", "answer": " Darth Plagueis."}
{"question": "What is the ability to manipulate the thoughts and perceptions of others in a broader sense, beyond the Jedi mind trick?", "answer": " Mind manipulation."}
{"question": "Which Force power allows a user to see the future but in an indistinct and ever-changing way?", "answer": " Force foresight."}
{"question": "What is the power to influence the physical world and control objects using the Force?", "answer": " Telekinesis."}
{"question": "Who uses the Force power of mind control to manipulate the thoughts of Anakin Skywalker in \u201cRevenge of the Sith\u201d?", "answer": " Darth Sidious (Emperor Palpatine)."}
{"question": "Who is the creator and original director of Star Wars?", "answer": " George Lucas."}
{"question": "What was the working title of \u201cReturn of the Jedi\u201d before it was officially named?", "answer": " \u201cRevenge of the Jedi.\u201d"}
{"question": "Which actor portrayed the iconic character Han Solo in the original trilogy?", "answer": " Harrison Ford."}
{"question": "What groundbreaking technology was used for the first time in the production of \u201cA New Hope\u201d?", "answer": " Industrial Light & Magic\u2019s computer-controlled motion-control camera."}
{"question": "What is the name of the studio in England where much of the original trilogy was filmed?", "answer": " Elstree Studios."}
{"question": "Who directed \u201cThe Empire Strikes Back\u201d?", "answer": " Irvin Kershner."}
{"question": "Which famous composer created the music for the Star Wars saga?", "answer": " John Williams."}
{"question": "What inspired George Lucas to create the character of Yoda?", "answer": " Albert Einstein\u2019s appearance and demeanor."}
{"question": "In which country was the Tatooine desert scenes filmed for the original trilogy?", "answer": " Tunisia."}
{"question": "Who is the voice behind the iconic droid R2-D2?", "answer": " Sound designer Ben Burtt."}
{"question": "What real-world military aircraft inspired the design of the Rebel Alliance\u2019s Incom T-65 X-wing starfighter?", "answer": " The P-51 Mustang."}
{"question": "Which actor played the role of Darth Vader in the original trilogy?", "answer": " David Prowse (body) and James Earl Jones (voice)."}
{"question": "What was the original release title of \u201cA New Hope\u201d before it was retitled after its success?", "answer": " \u201cStar Wars.\u201d"}
{"question": "Who designed the original Star Wars logo?", "answer": " Suzy Rice."}
{"question": "What is the name of the creature that served as the model for the Tauntaun in \u201cThe Empire Strikes Back\u201d?", "answer": " An Alaskan Malamute dog."}
{"question": "What company produced the practical effects for the original trilogy, including the creation of Yoda?", "answer": " Stuart Freeborn and his team at Elstree Studios."}
{"question": "What major technology innovation was used in \u201cThe Phantom Menace\u201d to create realistic CGI characters?", "answer": " The introduction of the first fully digital, photo-realistic character: Jar Jar Binks."}
{"question": "Who composed the iconic music for the Star Wars saga?", "answer": " John Williams."}
{"question": "What is the name of the main theme that plays during the opening crawl of each Star Wars film?", "answer": " \u201cMain Title\u201d or \u201cStar Wars Main Theme.\u201d"}
{"question": "What musical instrument is prominently featured in the Imperial March, Darth Vader\u2019s theme?", "answer": " Brass instruments, especially the brass section."}
{"question": "What is the name of the cantina band playing in Mos Eisley in \u201cA New Hope\u201d?", "answer": " Figrin D\u2019an and the Modal Nodes (or the Cantina Band)."}
{"question": "Which piece of music accompanies the intense lightsaber duel between Darth Vader and Luke Skywalker in \u201cThe Empire Strikes Back\u201d?", "answer": " \u201cDuel of the Fates.\u201d"}
{"question": "What is the emotional and poignant piece associated with the binary sunset scene on Tatooine?", "answer": " \u201cBinary Sunset\u201d or \u201cThe Force Theme.\u201d"}
{"question": "In \u201cReturn of the Jedi,\u201d what song does Sy Snootles sing during Jabba the Hutt\u2019s palace scene?", "answer": " \u201cLapti Nek.\u201d"}
{"question": "What is the name of the hymn-like piece played during Princess Leia\u2019s medal ceremony at the end of \u201cA New Hope\u201d?", "answer": " \u201cThrone Room and End Title.\u201d"}
{"question": "Which piece of music is associated with Yoda\u2019s first appearance and his wise teachings?", "answer": " \u201cYoda\u2019s Theme.\u201d"}
{"question": "What is the name of the stirring music that plays during the Battle of Hoth in \u201cThe Empire Strikes Back\u201d?", "answer": " \u201cThe Battle of Hoth.\u201d"}
{"question": "What is the name of the eerie choral piece that plays when Anakin Skywalker turns to the dark side in \u201cRevenge of the Sith\u201d?", "answer": " \u201cAnakin\u2019s Dark Deeds.\u201d"}
{"question": "Which composition accompanies the thrilling speeder bike chase through the forest moon of Endor in \u201cReturn of the Jedi\u201d?", "answer": " \u201cSpeeder Bike Chase.\u201d"}
{"question": "What is the name of the lively song played during the podrace scene in \u201cThe Phantom Menace\u201d?", "answer": " \u201cDuel of the Fates.\u201d"}
{"question": "In \u201cThe Force Awakens,\u201d what is the name of Rey\u2019s Theme?", "answer": " \u201cRey\u2019s Theme.\u201d"}
{"question": "Which piece of music is associated with the Sith Lord Darth Maul and his double-bladed lightsaber duel in \u201cThe Phantom Menace\u201d?", "answer": " \u201cDuel of the Fates.\u201d"}
{"question": "What is the name of the haunting composition played during the Order 66 sequence in \u201cRevenge of the Sith\u201d?", "answer": " \u201cAnakin\u2019s Betrayal.\u201d"}
{"question": "Which track is played during the iconic scene where Luke Skywalker stares at the twin suns on Tatooine in \u201cA New Hope\u201d?", "answer": " \u201cBinary Sunset\u201d or \u201cThe Force Theme.\u201d"}
{"question": "What Marvel Comics character makes a brief appearance in \u201cThe Empire Strikes Back\u201d as part of the Rebel Alliance?", "answer": " Doctor Aphra."}
{"question": "In \u201cThe Phantom Menace,\u201d which Star Wars character appears as a member of the Galactic Senate and resembles E.T. from the movie \u201cE.T. the Extra-Terrestrial\u201d?", "answer": " E.T. species."}
{"question": "What is the name of the character voiced by Daniel Craig in \u201cThe Force Awakens\u201d who succumbs to Jedi mind tricks?", "answer": " Stormtrooper JB-007 (James Bond reference)."}
{"question": "In \u201cSolo: A Star Wars Story,\u201d which iconic Star Wars bounty hunter makes a surprise cameo during the recruitment scene?", "answer": " Bossk."}
{"question": "Which Star Wars character makes an appearance as a hologram in the Disney+ series \u201cThe Mandalorian\u201d and is voiced by Mark Hamill?", "answer": " Luke Skywalker."}
{"question": "What animated series features characters from the Star Wars saga teaming up with Scooby-Doo and the gang?", "answer": " \u201cScooby-Doo! and the Curse of the 13th Ghost.\u201d"}
{"question": "In \u201cThe Last Jedi,\u201d what is the name of the codebreaker on Canto Bight who is a master codebreaker?", "answer": " DJ (played by Benicio del Toro)."}
{"question": "In \u201cRogue One: A Star Wars Story,\u201d which character from the animated series \u201cStar Wars: The Clone Wars\u201d makes a live-action appearance?", "answer": " Saw Gerrera."}
{"question": "What Star Wars character is mentioned in the film \u201cBlade: Trinity\u201d as having inspired the vampire language?", "answer": " Yoda."}
{"question": "In \u201cThe Force Awakens,\u201d what character does Rey envision herself becoming during her vision in Maz Kanata\u2019s castle?", "answer": " Darth Vader."}
{"question": "In \u201cThe Rise of Skywalker,\u201d which character from the prequel trilogy makes a surprise return as a Sith loyalist?", "answer": " Darth Sidious (Emperor Palpatine)."}
{"question": "What is the name of the Star Wars-themed episode in \u201cThe Simpsons,\u201d where the Simpson family goes to a galaxy far, far away?", "answer": " \u201cMarge vs. the Monorail.\u201d"}
{"question": "In \u201cSolo: A Star Wars Story,\u201d what is the name of Lando Calrissian\u2019s droid co-pilot that resembles a feminine protocol droid?", "answer": " L3-37."}
{"question": "In \u201cThe Clone Wars\u201d animated series, what famous bounty hunter from \u201cStar Wars: The Clone Wars\u201d makes a cameo appearance as a young Boba Fett?", "answer": " Cad Bane."}
{"question": "Which actor from the \u201cHarry Potter\u201d film series portrays General Hux in the sequel trilogy?", "answer": " Domhnall Gleeson."}
{"question": "In \u201cThe Rise of Skywalker,\u201d which alien species from the animated series \u201cStar Wars Rebels\u201d is briefly shown celebrating the defeat of the Final Order?", "answer": " Loth-cat."}
{"question": "What is the name of the Marvel Comics series that features characters from the Star Wars universe meeting characters from the Marvel Universe?", "answer": " \u201cStar Wars: The Screaming Citadel.\u201d"}
{"question": "What Sith Lord is responsible for the creation of the Galactic Empire and the fall of the Jedi Order?", "answer": " Darth Sidious (Emperor Palpatine)."}
{"question": "Who is the primary antagonist in \u201cThe Phantom Menace\u201d and is revealed to be a Sith apprentice?", "answer": " Darth Maul."}
{"question": "In \u201cThe Empire Strikes Back,\u201d who is revealed to be the father of Luke Skywalker?", "answer": " Darth Vader."}
{"question": "What is the name of the bounty hunter who captures Han Solo in \u201cThe Empire Strikes Back\u201d?", "answer": " Boba Fett."}
{"question": "In \u201cReturn of the Jedi,\u201d who is the crime lord of Tatooine and Jabba\u2019s Palace?", "answer": " Jabba the Hutt."}
{"question": "Which Separatist leader serves as the political head of the Confederacy of Independent Systems in the Clone Wars?", "answer": " Count Dooku (Darth Tyranus)."}
{"question": "What is the name of the dark side warrior who serves as the apprentice to Darth Tyranus in the Clone Wars?", "answer": " Asajj Ventress."}
{"question": "Who is the leader of the First Order in the sequel trilogy?", "answer": " Supreme Leader Snoke."}
{"question": "What is the nickname given to Anakin Skywalker after he turns to the dark side in \u201cRevenge of the Sith\u201d?", "answer": " Darth Vader."}
{"question": "Who is the Grand Moff and regional governor of the Galactic Empire who oversees the construction of the Death Star?", "answer": " Grand Moff Tarkin."}
{"question": "In \u201cThe Force Awakens,\u201d what dark side user commands the First Order and seeks to extinguish the Jedi?", "answer": " Kylo Ren."}
{"question": "What is the name of the Sith Lord who uses a double-bladed lightsaber and serves as Darth Sidious\u2019s apprentice in \u201cThe Phantom Menace\u201d?", "answer": " Darth Maul."}
{"question": "What is the nickname for the secret apprentice trained by Darth Vader in \u201cThe Force Unleashed\u201d video game?", "answer": " Starkiller (Galen Marek)."}
{"question": "Who is the cunning and ambitious Hutt crime lord who appears in \u201cThe Clone Wars\u201d animated series?", "answer": " Ziro the Hutt."}
{"question": "What is the name of the dark side organization led by Darth Sidious to manipulate galactic events?", "answer": " The Sith."}
{"question": "In \u201cRogue One: A Star Wars Story,\u201d who is the Imperial weapons expert overseeing the Death Star project?", "answer": " Orson Krennic."}
{"question": "Who is the leader of the Nightsisters on Dathomir and plays a significant role in the \u201cClone Wars\u201d animated series?", "answer": " Mother Talzin."}
{"question": "What is the name of the battle in \u201cA New Hope\u201d where the Rebel Alliance destroys the Death Star?", "answer": " Battle of Yavin."}
{"question": "In \u201cThe Empire Strikes Back,\u201d what is the Rebel Alliance\u2019s desperate last stand against the Empire on the icy planet Hoth called?", "answer": " Battle of Hoth."}
{"question": "What is the final confrontation between Luke Skywalker and Darth Vader in \u201cReturn of the Jedi\u201d known as?", "answer": " Battle of Endor (specifically, the duel on the second Death Star)."}
{"question": "Which battle in the Clone Wars serves as the climax of \u201cAttack of the Clones,\u201d featuring the Jedi, clones, and Separatist forces?", "answer": " Battle of Geonosis."}
{"question": "What is the name of the pivotal battle in \u201cThe Force Awakens\u201d where the Resistance destroys Starkiller Base?", "answer": " Battle of Starkiller Base."}
{"question": "In \u201cRogue One: A Star Wars Story,\u201d what is the name of the battle where the Rebel Alliance steals the Death Star plans?", "answer": " Battle of Scarif."}
{"question": "What is the major confrontation in \u201cThe Clone Wars\u201d animated series where the Republic and Separatists fight on the planet Umbara?", "answer": " Battle of Umbara."}
{"question": "In \u201cThe Phantom Menace,\u201d what is the battle between the Naboo and Gungan forces against the Trade Federation on Naboo called?", "answer": " Battle of Naboo."}
{"question": "What is the conflict in \u201cRevenge of the Sith\u201d where Anakin Skywalker and Obi-Wan Kenobi confront Count Dooku and General Grievous?", "answer": " Battle of Coruscant."}
{"question": "What is the battle in \u201cThe Rise of Skywalker\u201d where the Resistance faces the Final Order fleet led by Emperor Palpatine?", "answer": " Battle of Exegol."}
{"question": "In \u201cThe Clone Wars\u201d animated series, what battle takes place on the planet Ryloth, focusing on the liberation of the Twi\u2019lek people?", "answer": " Battle of Ryloth."}
{"question": "What is the skirmish in \u201cSolo: A Star Wars Story\u201d where Tobias Beckett and his crew attempt to steal coaxium from a train?", "answer": " Conveyex Heist."}
{"question": "What is the battle on the forest moon of Endor in \u201cReturn of the Jedi\u201d where the Rebel Alliance destroys the second Death Star?", "answer": " Battle of Endor."}
{"question": "In \u201cThe Clone Wars\u201d animated series, what is the name of the battle where the clones, led by Captain Rex, face droid forces on a space station?", "answer": " Battle of Anaxes."}
{"question": "What is the skirmish in \u201cThe Mandalorian\u201d where the Mandalorian and his allies face off against Imperial forces and Moff Gideon?", "answer": " Battle of Nevarro."}
{"question": "In \u201cThe Clone Wars\u201d animated series, what is the name of the battle where the Republic defends the planet Christophsis against Separatist forces?", "answer": " Battle of Christophsis."}
{"question": "What is the major conflict in \u201cThe Force Awakens\u201d where the Resistance confronts the First Order on the planet Starkiller Base?", "answer": " Assault on Starkiller Base."}
{"question": "What is the name of the scavenger on the desert planet Jakku, who becomes a key protagonist in \u201cThe Force Awakens\u201d?", "answer": " Rey."}
{"question": "What is the name of the First Order stormtrooper who defects and takes on the name Finn?", "answer": " FN-2187."}
{"question": "In \u201cThe Force Awakens,\u201d which droid holds a crucial piece of the map leading to Luke Skywalker\u2019s location?", "answer": " BB-8."}
{"question": "What is the name of the mysterious dark side warrior who wields a unique crossguard lightsaber?", "answer": " Kylo Ren."}
{"question": "In \u201cThe Force Awakens,\u201d what organization is formed to resist the First Order?", "answer": " The Resistance."}
{"question": "What is the name of the planet that was destroyed by the Starkiller Base, the superweapon of the First Order?", "answer": " Hosnian Prime."}
{"question": "Who is the wise and experienced former stormtrooper who guides Rey and Finn in \u201cThe Force Awakens\u201d?", "answer": " Han Solo."}
{"question": "What is the name of the Supreme Leader of the First Order in \u201cThe Force Awakens\u201d?", "answer": " Supreme Leader Snoke."}
{"question": "What is the primary mission of the Resistance in \u201cThe Force Awakens\u201d?", "answer": " To find Luke Skywalker and seek his help."}
{"question": "In \u201cThe Force Awakens,\u201d what is the name of the planet where Maz Kanata\u2019s castle is located?", "answer": " Takodana."}
{"question": "What character from the original trilogy is revealed to have become a General in the Resistance by \u201cThe Force Awakens\u201d?", "answer": " Leia Organa."}
{"question": "What is the name of the freighter piloted by Han Solo and Chewbacca in \u201cThe Force Awakens\u201d?", "answer": " The Millennium Falcon."}
{"question": "Who is the commander of the First Order\u2019s Starkiller Base in \u201cThe Force Awakens\u201d?", "answer": " General Hux."}
{"question": "In \u201cThe Force Awakens,\u201d what is Finn\u2019s role during the attack on Starkiller Base?", "answer": " He helps lead the ground assault to disable the shields."}
{"question": "What is the name of the resistance pilot who plays a significant role in the aerial assault on Starkiller Base?", "answer": " Poe Dameron."}
{"question": "What piece of information does R2-D2 reveal near the end of \u201cThe Force Awakens\u201d?", "answer": " The missing portion of the map leading to Luke Skywalker."}
{"question": "In the final lightsaber duel in \u201cThe Force Awakens,\u201d who is mortally wounded by Kylo Ren?", "answer": " Han Solo."}
